DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宮飯》
Izutsumi, Chilchuck…
莞苞、奇爾查克
Could you slow down a bit?
腳步能放慢一點嗎？
Cracks are all over the floor, and it's hard to walk.
地面有太多縫隙了，很難行走
I didn't notice.
我都沒注意到
Let's take a break.
暫時休息一下吧
What is this? An old folks' stroll?
這是老年人在散步嗎？
Something's bothering me.
有件事讓我很在意
In our current forms,
我們現在的樣貌
how different are our actual ages from how old we look?
實際年齡跟外表年齡差了多少？
Laios, how old are you now?
萊歐斯，你現在幾歲？
I'm 26.
26歲
Senshi, how old does Laios look to you now?
先西，你覺得現在的萊歐斯 看起來像幾歲？
Around 60, maybe?
60歲左右？
They say a dwarf lives 2.5 times longer than a tall-man.
據說矮人的壽命是長身人的兩倍半
So 26 years for a tall-man…
如果長身人是26歲…
is like 65 for a dwarf.
那矮人就是65歲左右
So, our appearance reflects our actual age.
所以外表反映出了我們的實際年齡
What really concerns me is our remaining lifespan.
我更在意的是剩下的壽命
Do we age at the same pace as before our transformation,
變老的速度跟產生變化之前相同嗎？
or do we age according to our new forms?
還是以變化後的樣貌為準？
Marcille, you act like this is none of your concern.
瑪露希爾，你現在雖然 一臉事不關己的樣子
But if the latter is true,
如果是後者
the average lifespan for us half-foots is 50!
我們半身人的平均壽命是50歲！
In less than 40 years, you'll be all wrinkled and die!
你在40年之內就會滿臉皺紋 然後死去！
What?!
什麼？
WRINKLECILLE
（皺巴巴希爾）
Is the lifespan really that short?
壽命那麼短？
I thought you could live until 100.
不是可以活100年左右嗎？
Some do, but…
的確有人可以活很久…
It's only a small percentage.
但是比例非常少
I was just joking.
我是開玩笑的啦
My point is, if that's true, these mushrooms are too convenient.
我想說的是，若真是如此 這種蘑菇實在太方便了
There are loads of people who would pay a fortune to change their race,
願意花大錢變成其他種族的人 可是多到數不清
but I've never seen those mushrooms for sale anywhere.
但我從沒在市場看過那種菇類
In other words, this transformation must be temporary,
也就是說，這種變化只是暫時性的
or it comes with nasty side effects.
不然就是會有糟糕的副作用
Side effects, huh?
副作用嗎？
That's a possibility.
有可能
I was hoping we could make use of it somehow,
我還想說能不能拿來善用
but I guess it's not that simple.
事情果然沒那麼順利啊
Make use of it how?
你是想做什麼事啊？
Do you want to become a demi-human or something?
是想變成亞人之類的嗎？
T-That's not it.
不是那樣啦
I was thinking about Falin.
我是在想法琳的事啦
Falin?
法琳？
This is just a what-if, but…
這只是假設喔
Say everything works out, and we manage to defeat the lunatic magician.
若一切順利，我們打倒狂亂魔術師…
I repent.
我不會再這樣做了
Falin regains herself.
法琳就能恢復正常
What have I been doing?
我做了什麼啊？
-Hurray!
-萬歲！
We return to the surface.
接著我們回到地表
Honestly, we had such a rough time!
天啊，真的吃了不少苦頭呢！
People will be terrified.
人們會感到害怕
Right?
對吧？
I think it'll be tough for her to remain a dragon from the waist down.
她的下半身是龍，應該會很難生活吧
-You stupid-- -Hold on!
-笨蛋… -等等！
Let's hear him out.
再聽他繼續說下去吧
I've thought of hiding the lower part of her body inside a hole.
我也想過要挖個洞，讓她藏住下半身
Welcome!
歡迎光臨！
However,
不過啊
a large monster can't survive in a village with little mana.
大型魔物是無法 在魔力稀薄的村莊生存的
Just like a fish can't survive outside of water,
就像魚不能活在沒有水的地方
Falin might not be able to survive in a village.
法琳可能打從一開始 就沒辦法在村莊內生活
And that's where
所以呢
those Changeling mushrooms come into play.
利用這種調換菇
If we can somehow change her lower body to a smaller dragon,
只要能把她的下半身 變成比較小型的龍
Falin might be able to live comfortably in a human village!
法琳或許也能在村子度日！
-What-- -What an optimistic guy!
-什麼… -這傢伙好樂觀啊！
Mušḫuššu!
怒蛇！
Well, I won't deny that I also have a wish to transform.
但是啊，我也不否認自己想變身看看
Tall-men are just so unremarkable and dull…
長身人很平凡，沒什麼特徵…
Hey, don't you hear that strange noise?
我問你，有沒有聽到 什麼奇怪的聲音？
No. It's probably the sound of dwarf relics.
沒有，不是矮人的遺物發出來的嗎？
It's not that.
不對
It sounds like rocks striking against each other.
像是石頭碰撞的聲音
And it seems like it's slowly getting closer.
似乎漸漸往這邊靠近了
I know.
我知道了
Gargoyles!
是石像鬼！
Didn't you close the door properly?
你沒確實把門關上嗎？
W-We need to get out of here quickly!
我們得快點逃！
They're getting closer!
石像鬼越來越接近了！
If we don't do something, they'll keep coming after us.
要是什麼都不做，不管逃到哪裡 我們都會被當成目標
We should ambush them.
該埋伏在這裡並迎擊
B-But…
可是…
I'll distract the enemies.
我來分散敵人的注意力
Chilchuck, hold the pot.
奇爾查克，你拿好鍋子
Izutsumi, slip around behind them.
莞苞繞到敵人背後
Senshi, wait for the right moment.
先西則是伺機而動
Marcille, how close are the enemies?
瑪露希爾，敵人離我們多遠？
Like I said,
所以我就說了
they're right there!
已經近在眼前了！
Laios!
萊歐斯！
Damn it!
糟了！
Everyone, watch out!
各位，小心點！
Do you get why the first thing I do is take cover?
你現在明白為什麼 我每次都會馬上跑去躲起來了吧？
Don't hang around our feet.
別在大家的腳邊晃來晃去
Easier said than done…
說得倒容易…
Forget it! You're still as clumsy as ever.
真是的！你還是老樣子 總是笨手笨腳的
Come here!
過來這邊！
What is this smoke?
這些煙是怎麼回事？
Is it one of your magic?
是你的魔法嗎？
Are you two hurt?
你們倆沒受傷吧？
No! The sword just passed between our arms!
沒事，劍只是從我們的 手臂間穿了過去而已！
Good.
太好了
Pass me Kensuke, would you?
能把劍助拿給我嗎？
Sure.
好
Did it always look like that?
本來是長這樣嗎？
Nope.
不是
Has the shape of the sword changed?
劍的形狀變了？
Was that smoke…
難道剛才的煙…
-Spores from Changelings?
-源自調換菇的孢子？
B-But I don't see a ring of mushrooms anywhere.
可是我沒看到蘑菇圍成的圈啊
It passed through a circle we formed with our arms.
那從我們手臂圍成的圈穿過去了
Does that mean…
你是說…
They keep flying away!
竟然到處亂飛！
Everyone!
大家！
Hold hands and make a ring right now!
現在馬上把手牽起來，圍成一個圈！
Read the situation before you say that!
你看清楚情況再說話啦！
I did!
我有啊！
Now what?
然後呢？
What do we do?
接下來該怎麼做？
We'll get a Gargoyle to pass through our ring.
要讓石像鬼 從我們用手臂圍成的圈穿過去
If my guess is correct,
如果我猜得沒錯
the Gargoyle will transform!
到時候石像鬼的樣子就會改變！
Here it comes! Dodge!
要來了！快閃開！
There's a wall on that side! This way!
那邊是牆壁吧！過來這邊！
Ow!
好痛…
I'll tear in two!
我要裂成兩半了！
Owie.
有夠痛的
It's stuck!
石像鬼卡住了！
Now, surround it quickly!
就是現在，趕快上前圍住！
We did it! Where's the Gargoyle?
成功了！石像鬼呢？
Look!
快看！
That's the Gargoyle?
這是石像鬼嗎？
It really transformed!
真的改變了！
I see. The Changelings caused this.
我懂了，這就是調換菇的效果
So nonliving things change faster.
若是非生物，就能變化得更快
Laios!
萊歐斯！
Are you okay?
沒事吧？
It hurts, but I'll manage.
雖然很疼，但我沒事
Dwarves have sturdy bodies.
矮人的身體還真結實
Damn it.
可惡
That one won't come down.
那傢伙遲遲不下來呢
How can we get it to pass through our arms?
該怎麼讓那石像鬼穿過我們的手臂？
-Marcille. -Huh?
-瑪露希爾 -什麼？
-Give me your hand for a bit.
-把手給我一下
-It should work. -Um.
-應該可行 -那個…
-Let's do it. -All right!
-來吧 -好！
We're going to get up close to it,
來縮短和那傢伙的距離吧
and provoke it into attacking us!
我們要誘導石像鬼攻擊！
-Hey, what do I-- -Run in sync with the call!
-嘿，我要… -配合口號一起跑！
Here we go!
要上了！
-One, two…
-一、二…
Here it comes! Are you ready?
要來囉！做好覺悟了嗎？
Ready for what?!
覺悟？
-Ready, set…
-預備…
Fly, Marcille!
飛吧，瑪露希爾！
It's over.
結束了
There was nothing to it.
沒什麼問題
All we had to do was wash the spores off our bodies to turn back.
只要把附著在身上孢子洗乾淨 就會恢復原狀了
It feels wrong.
有點令人抗拒
Don't worry about it. It's just water.
別在意，這只是水
You should wash them off thoroughly.
要徹底洗乾淨比較好
Right now, we're like seedbeds for mushrooms.
我們現在是蘑菇的溫床
Now I understand why those mushrooms have this characteristic.
我終於曉得為什麼調換菇 會有這種特性了
When animals have their forms changed by Changelings…
當動物被調換菇改變了樣貌後…
-Run!
-快逃！
They're hated by their own kind.
就會被同類討厭
They die.
然後死去
And they become new Changelings.
接著變成新的調換菇
It's quite the side effect.
這副作用可真慘
Unlike Gargoyles, it'll take time for us to turn back.
跟石像鬼不同 我們要恢復原狀需要花點時間
Let's prepare a meal as we wait.
邊準備料理邊等吧
Of course.
當然好
Kensuke,look at how you've changed.
劍助，你竟然變成這副模樣
I doubt it was the mushrooms that turned the insides into a key, but…
儘管很難想像是調換菇的效果 讓其內部變成鑰匙…
Will it revert if I give it a wash?
用水洗過後就會變回來了吧？
What are we having today?
今天吃什麼？
We still have some dumplings left, so we'll boil them.
餃子還有剩，就煮那個吧
That again.
又是那個喔
Do you have a problem?
有什麼問題嗎？
Not really. I'm just tired of them.
沒什麼，只是吃膩了
-Tired of them? -She sure is a free spirit.
-吃膩了？ -那傢伙還真是率性而為
I'll try cooking them differently.
那就改變料理方式吧
Heat oil in a pan, and gently place the dumplings in it.
在平底鍋中熱油 接著輕輕把餃子放進去
H-Hot!
好燙喔！
When the wrappers are golden brown, take them out and let the oil drain.
外皮炸成金黃色後，夾起來瀝油
Izutsumi is a light eater
莞苞不僅食量小
and never touches something she doesn't like.
而且碰到不喜歡的東西就絕對不吃
To make sure she eats enough, I have to put in the time and effort.
為了讓她多吃點，得多下點功夫
What do you think, Izutsumi?
怎麼樣啊？莞苞
You just fried them?
你只是把這些炸過？
Stop that!
別這樣！
Just maybe…
搞不好…
It changed its shape!
形狀改變了！
Just as I thought, it seems like the mouth acts as a ring.
果然如此，看來嘴巴有蘑菇圈的效果
And there are so many varieties of dumplings.
而且餃子的種類很豐富
What if I eat one and end up growing mushrooms in my stomach?
要是吃了之後 連胃裡都長出蘑菇該怎麼辦？
We had the Hippogriff's meat, and that didn't happen.
我們吃了鷹馬肉之後 不也什麼都沒發生嗎？
Digestion is quite powerful.
消化系統可是無敵的
Now, help set the dishes.
來，幫忙擺餐具
It's done!
完成了！
DUMPLINGS TRANSFORMED BY A CHANGELING FAIRY RING
（藉由仙女環調換的變身餃子）
There are so many types.
種類還真多
This one has Barometz meat in it.
這裡面有植物羊的肉耶
Mutton, huh?
有羊肉啊？
So the filling changes too.
所以是連食材也變了
This one's got cheese inside!
裡面有起司！
This one's sweet.
這個是甜的
What meat is this?
這是什麼肉？
Your legs are just too long!
你的腳太長了啦！
My body's back to normal!
身體變回來了！
Damn it.
可惡
What an awful way to wake up.
醒來的方式太糟糕了
Thank goodness.
太好了
I'm so glad.
真的太好了
Well then, we should get going soon.
那差不多該準備出發了
You should change into something lighter.
換上涼快的衣服比較好
This floor is warm.
這一層很溫暖
The temperature is conducive to creature reproduction.
這氣溫讓生物很容易繁殖
But I'm not sure if there are any living things ahead in this environment.
但在這種環境下 不曉得前方有沒有生物
I should have made sausages or something.
早知道就先做些香腸之類的食物了
Speaking of which, didn't you make some with Red Dragon meat?
這麼說起來 你之前不是用炎龍的肉做了嗎？
I did.
是啊
BONELESS DRAGON HAM
（去骨龍火腿）
But I lost them.
但弄丟了
Is that so?
這樣啊
Never mind.
是沒差啦
I don't like it when it's hot.
真不希望太熱啊
Why is your sword wrapped in a cloth?
你為什麼要用布把劍包起來？
Huh? That's because…
什麼？這是因為…
Show me.
讓我看一下
No, I can't do that.
不要，那樣我會很困擾
Show me!
給我看就對了！
What should we do with him?
我們該拿這傢伙怎麼辦？
Should we form a ring around him and beat him up?
要不要大家圍成一圈，揍他一頓？
Go wash it off right now.
現在馬上去用水洗乾淨
How are things over there?
那邊怎麼樣？
All I see is a strange building.
只有一棟奇怪的建築物
I don't see any other paths.
看起來沒有其他路能走
A strange building?
奇怪的建築物？
It's probably an automatic trolley.
很可能是自動礦車
Let's take a peek inside.
看一下裡面吧
I bet it won't move anymore.
這已經不會動了吧
If you dismantle it and sell it, you can fetch a pretty good price.
如果解體拿去變賣 一定能賣個好價錢
It moved!
動了！
Senshi, what did you do?
先西，你做了什麼？
Nothing.
什麼也沒做
Maybe it's the type that moves when someone boards it.
可能是只要有人坐上去 就會發動的設計
There's a description here, so I'll read it.
這邊寫了一些說明，老夫來看看
Take a seat.
你們就坐著吧
There isn't much written here.
沒有寫什麼重要的事
It doesn't feel dangerous so far,
不過目前也感受不到危險
so let's ride it as far as it goes.
就看礦車能跑多遠吧
Maybe I'll brew some tea.
來泡個茶好了
What's that?
那些是什麼？
Roasted Dryad seeds.
炒過的樹精種子
Is the magic circle ready?
魔法陣畫好了嗎？
I think so.
應該好了
I can't say for sure if it's working.
但我不確定有沒有在運作
It's slow, but it seems to be heating up.
雖然很慢，但看來確實有在加熱
By the way, Laios,
對了，萊歐斯
why did you and your sister become adventurers?
你們兄妹為什麼會成為冒險者？
Huh? Me?
什麼？我嗎？
You don't strike me as someone who dreams of making a fortune.
你們看起來也不是 夢想一夜致富的那種人
It's a long story, but…
這說來話長…
When I was in my teens, I got fed up with my village.
十幾歲的時候 我對故鄉的村子感到厭惡
And I went to a school in the town and joined the army.
於是到城鎮的學校就讀 接著加入了軍隊
But in the end, I didn't fit in there either.
但到頭來我也不適應那裡
And I got picked up by a caravan that passed through the town.
後來被經過城鎮的商隊收留
So he's a deserter?
所以他是逃兵？
I slowly drifted south, taking odd jobs along the way.
我一邊打雜，一邊前往南方的各處
Falin was boarding at a nearby magic school,
法琳就住在那附近的魔法學校
so I dropped by to see her.
我本來只是打算去見她一面
But she insisted on joining me.
但她無論如何都想跟我走
And together, we reached this island.
所以我們最後一起抵達了這座島
When we first arrived on this island, gold-peeling was thriving.
我們剛來時，這裡有很多剝金者
And there was plenty of escorting work.
因此有大量徵求護衛的工作
Then, we just stayed and hung around the dungeon.
然後我們從此就經常身在迷宮
That's how I ended up here.
一直到現在
What a complete lack of foresight.
真是缺乏遠見
You're one thing, but why did you let your sister go with you?
你就算了，為何連妹妹都一起來了？
She could've had a better life at school.
她在學校能過得更好吧？
Falin's childhood wasn't very fortunate.
法琳的童年過得不怎麼幸福
She had a talent for magic, which she was shunned for.
她有魔法天賦，因此被他人排擠
I couldn't stand the environment.
我對周遭的人感到厭惡
So I left the village a year before she did.
所以早她一年離開了那座村莊
Until she entered the magic school, no,
直到她進入魔法學校就讀，不
until she met Marcille,
直到她遇見瑪露希爾之前
she had her meals all alone.
她一直都是孤伶伶地吃飯
It breaks my heart to think about it.
一想到她當時的樣子 我的內心就隱隱作痛
Well, Falin's spirit was much stronger than mine,
不過呢，她的內心遠比我堅強許多
so maybe it didn't bother her too much.
搞不好其實一點都不在意
But that's why I made a promise to myself to never abandon her again.
所以我決定不會再拋下法琳
At least, not until someone else shows up whom she wants to be with.
至少在她找到 能陪伴在自己身旁的對象之前
What the heck? Gross!
幹嘛啊？很噁心耶！
Falin…
法琳…
used to bring me a lot of things.
常常會撿很多東西給我
Strange nuts.
比如奇特的果實
And odd plants.
或是莫名其妙的草
I've always wondered why she kept bringing them to me, but…
以前還想說為什麼老是要送來給我…
She probably wanted to eat them with you, Marcille.
因為她想跟你一起吃吧，瑪露希爾
I can't wait…
我等不及…
to share meals with her again.
再和她一起吃飯了
You'll be able to soon.
你的願望很快就會實現的
The way I see it,
在老夫看來
Falin is like bacon and eggs right now.
現在的法琳就像培根蛋
We once compared souls to eggs.
我們以前曾把靈魂比喻成蛋
A sunny side up rests on top of strips of bacon.
將蛋放在培根上
They're stuck together, but it looks like we can peel them apart nicely.
雖然黏在一塊 但似乎也能將其徹底分離
That's Falin.
那就是法琳
Compared to that, Izutsumi is more like an omelet
相比之下，要形容莞苞的話
with ingredients mixed inside.
就像是有加料的歐姆蛋
With effort, you might be able to remove the ingredients,
雖然只要努力 就能將食材全部挑出來
but it's easy to imagine the egg getting broken up.
但能想像蛋會被弄得稀巴爛
So, in Izutsumi's case,
所以莞苞的情況
we'll have to find a more careful and complicated approach.
必須更慎重地找出一個複雜的順序
In other words,
換句話說
if we cut off the dragon waist down,
只要把她下半身的龍切除
can we turn Falin back into her human form?
就能把法琳就恢復成人類的樣貌？
It's not that simple, is it?
應該沒那麼單純吧？
That day,
在那一天
I preserved some of the Dragon meat,
即使老夫用龍肉做了易保存的食物
but it all turned back into flesh and merged with Falin.
但那些仍全都回歸血肉 並和法琳融合
On the other hand, some of the meat didn't turn back into a dragon.
但另一方面 有部分的肉並沒有回到龍的身上
It's the parts that we ate at dinner.
就是我們當成晚餐吃掉的部位
Meat that has been digested by other creatures loses its identity.
被其他生物消化掉的肉會失去自我
This is the only clear law in this dungeon
那是在這座生死界線模糊的迷宮中
where the line between life and death is blurred.
唯一一條明確的準則吧
In that case, if we consume all the dragon parts,
這麼說來，只要把龍的部分全部吃掉
we may be able to drive out the soul of the dragon.
或許就能只把龍的靈魂驅除
Y-You know,
該怎麼說呢？
I'm surprised to hear that from you, Senshi.
沒想到你會說那種話，先西
I thought you were against that sort of thing.
我以為你會反對這一類的事情
I'm still against resurrecting people.
老夫直到現在仍反對復活人類
However, Falin is alive now.
不過法琳現在還活著
And you just want to release her from the dungeon.
而你們想將她從這座迷宮中解放出來
I'll gladly help you with that.
那老夫很樂意幫忙
Eat the dragon parts.
吃掉龍的部分
B-But…
但是那樣…
how many meals would that make?
到底要吃幾餐？
-That's your problem?
-那不是重點吧？
What else would it be?
是超重要的重點啦！
It's the most promising method we've got so far!
這是目前為止最有希望的方法了！
Do you have a better idea?
難道有其他替代方案嗎？
Consuming a creature you've killed to make it your own.
為了讓殺掉的生物 成為自己的一部分而將其吃掉
Why didn't I realize it sooner?
有道理，為什麼我沒有早點注意到？
It's what we've been doing all along!
這就是我們一直在做的事啊！
But it's massive.
不過身軀相當巨大
Even if the five of us push to consume a kilogram each day,
即使五個人每天努力吃一公斤
it'll still take us over a decade to finish it all.
也要花超過十年才吃得完
Do you honestly think I can handle eating a kilogram?
你覺得我能吃下一公斤嗎？
And considering Falin's condition, we definitely don't have time for that.
考量到法琳的身體狀況 我們絕對沒有那麼多時間
So, just ask others to help.
那就請其他人幫忙吧
It's time to make full use of the connections you've built.
這正是你建立的人脈派上用場的時候
You're banking on my connections for this?
你確定要指望我的人脈？
It's not like you're without any.
並非完全沒有吧
Can't you think of anyone?
你有沒有想到誰？
The orcs.
那些半獸人
They'll likely eat a fair amount and seem like a promising choice.
他們看起來食量很大，值得期待
The inhabitants of the Golden Castle.
還有黃金城堡的居民
They might not have the heartiest appetite,
雖然稍微缺乏食慾
but their numbers and livestock can compensate for that.
但應該能靠人口和家畜數量彌補
Then there's Namari, Shuro, and their groups.
還有娜瑪莉和修洛他們
Those two will lend a hand if we appeal to their emotions.
只要對他們動之以情就行了
And Kabru seemed interested in trying monster food.
還有喀布爾 他好像也對魔物料理很感興趣
That's all I can come up with at the moment.
目前想到的就是那些人
That's quite a list.
這不是有很多嗎？
But we're hardly enough to consume the entire dragon.
但離吃完還差得遠呢
I wish we could also have another troop.
還想要大概一支中隊的人數
But at least
不過呢
we've got clear goals now.
這樣一來接下來的目標就清楚了
First, we release the Winged Lion from the heart of the dungeon.
一，將翼獅從最深處解放出來
Second,
二
with the Lion's aid, we neutralize the lunatic magician's power.
在翼獅的幫助下 使狂亂魔術師失去力量
Third,
三
we recruit people to assist us in consuming Falin's dragon parts.
尋找願意一起吃法琳身上龍肉的夥伴
I'm suddenly feeling optimistic about this.
突然覺得一切可行呢
It's going to be one extravagant feast.
看來會有一場盛大的宴會呢
There are no troops inside the dungeon.
別妄想迷宮中有一支中隊的人數了
What's this sickening feeling?
怎麼突然覺得不太舒服？
The air in the dungeon is stale.
因為迷宮內的空氣十分混濁
While you guys were inside, it underwent another big transformation.
你們待在裡面時，這裡又變了許多
A transformation?
變了？
You'll get it once you see it.
看了就馬上會知道
Well, it's going to be an unpleasant transformation
不過呢，對後面的那群人來說
for the folks behind us, at least.
這一定是他們不樂見的變化吧
Don't eat stuff like that!
別吃那種東西！
What's all this racket?
還真吵啊
Walking Mushrooms.
走路菇
How about using them as a garnish for a steak
將法琳身上的龍肉做成肉排時
made from Falin's dragon parts?
拿這個當配菜怎麼樣？
Or should we make a stew instead?
還是做成燉菜比較好？
-The broth from the bones-- -Stop it!
-用骨頭熬出高湯… -別說了！
Now's not the time to be planning Falin menus!
現在不是思考法琳菜單的時候吧！
I'm hungry.
肚子餓了
Shall we prepare something?
來做些料理吧，好嗎？
I second that!
贊成！
Dungeon food.
迷宮飯
Eat or be eaten.
不是吃，就是被吃
There is no hierarchy.
迷宮裡沒有上下之分
Eating is a privilege for those who live.
唯有進食是生者的特權
Dungeon food.
迷宮飯
Oh, dungeon food.
哦，迷宮飯
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：黃琴喻